# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我和大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'll share with you...
# 大蒜烧肚条
Garlic and pork tripe strips stir-fry
# 首先我们准备新鲜的猪肚一个（约750克）
First of all, prepare a fresh pork tripe (about 750g)
# 市场上售卖的猪肚一般都是被摊主翻过来的
Pork tripe bought from the market is often turned inside out
# 这样看起来更有卖相，同样肥肠也是如此
It presents better that way, the same for pork intestine
# 下一步开始处理
Next step, process the tripe
# 首先我们用剪刀将猪肚剪开
First, cut the tripe open with scissors
# 这样更方便内外清洗和处理
This makes it easier to clean both the interior and exterior of the tripe
# 猪肚剪开之后再去除猪肚里面多余的油脂
Remove the excessive fat inside the tripe
# 这层油脂跟肥肠的不同它有一定的腥味
Different from port intestine, this layer of fat has a stinky odor
# 去除得约干净越好
So try your best eliminating it
# 手撕不动的同学也可以用剪刀剪掉
If you cannot tear it off, try scissors
# 肥油去除之后加入热水挼（搓）洗几遍
When done, rub the tripe thoroughly with hot water
# 这一步的目的是去除猪肚表层的胃液
Rubbing would wash off any unwanted gastric juice on the surface of the tripe
# 同学们注意这一步必须用热水挼 （抓）
Make sure that you rub with hot water...
# 否则剩余的肥油容易腻手
Or the fat residual might stick to your hand
# 同时对胃酸过敏的同学可以戴手套操作
People allergic to gastric acid may use gloves
# 以免对手造成腐蚀
It also protects your hands from the acid
# 下一步开始深度清理
Next, thoroughly clean tripe
#首先在盆中加入一把食用盐挼（抓）洗3分钟
Add a handful of salt, then rub it for 3 minutes
# 这一步是对猪肚的初步处理
This gives the tripe a primary processing
# 3分钟之后加入滚水清洗干净
After 3 minutes, pour in boiling water to rinse it off
# 清洗干净之后再次加入一大把食用盐
Add a generous handful of salt after draining the water
# 加入适量的高度白酒用力抓5分钟
Add some strong liquor to rub the tripe hard for another 5 minutes
# 这一步的目的是去除腥臭味
This should eliminate all the odor
# 中途再加入一小把干淀粉挼
Add some starch and continue rubbing the tripe
# 加干淀粉的目的是带走抓出来的黏液
Starch helps to remove the slime produced during the preparation process
# 温馨提示：同学们切记此过程比较棘手和辣手
Note that this step can burn your hands...
# 对胃酸过敏的同学和手上有伤口的同学请谨慎操作
Again, if you are allergic to gastric acid or wounded, execute this step with care and caution
# 5分钟之后加入滚水清洗干净备用
After 5 minutes, add boiling water to clean the tripe and set it aside
# 下一步开始准备煮猪肚是辅料
Next step, prepare the aromatics for boiling the tripe
# 准备生姜1小块切成姜片备用
Slice up a small chunk of ginger
# 准备大葱1根切成片备用
Also slice some scallions, set aside
# 碗中加入适量 的高度白酒
Add some strong baijiu liquor into the bowl
# 下一步开始煮猪肚
Next, boiling
# 首先我们在锅中加入大半锅清水
Add a lot of water into the wok
# 然后将处理好的猪肚冷水下锅开大火煮开
Add the tripe into the cold water directly, and then boil over high heat
# 大火烧开之后再撇去浮末
Skim off the scums after it boils
# 将猪肚焯水定型之后捞出
Take the tripe out
#然后将剩余的水倒入高压锅中备用
Transfer the boiled water to the pressure cooker
#没有高压锅的同学可以直接煮40分钟
If you do not have a pressure cooker, boil the tripe for 40 minutes in a regular pot
#下一步开始压猪肚
Next step: pressure cooking the tripe
# 将捞出的猪肚对半切开
Cut the tripe in half
# 然后将肚头上面的白色物质刮干净
Scrape off the white substances on the "head" of the tripe
# 这个部位非常腥臭必须去除干净
It is crucial to clean this place thoroughly to avoid bringing odor into the dish
# 处理干净之后放入高压锅里面上汽之后压8分钟
When done, put the tripe back to the pressure cooker to cook for another 8 minutes
# 同学们压制8分钟这个时长可以让猪肚口感爽脆不嫩不老
Remember that it takes 8 minutes to achieve the ideal crunchy texture for our dish that is neither too tender nor too chewy
# 喜欢有嚼劲的同学可以减少压制时间
If you prefer the tripe to be chewy, reduce the cooking time to your preference
# 8分钟之后捞出趁热改刀切成小条备用
After 8 minutes, take the tripe out
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, prepare the minor ingredients
# 准备莴笋半条
cut a half of celtuse
# 从中间切开之后再切成跟猪肚大小的条备用
in the middle then chop it into slices
# 准备大蒜50克切成小粒备用
Dice 50 gram garlic for later use
# 同学们大蒜主要是增香所用可以适当的多加一些
because the garlic is for adding flavor, you could add a little bit more
# 准备生姜1小块切成姜粒备用
Dice a chunk of ginger for later use
# 准备大葱1根切成小粒备用
Dice a spring onion for later use
# 最后准备大红椒半个切成小条备用
cut half of red pepper into small strips for later use
# 下一步开始制作
Now Let’s start cooking
# 首次我们把锅烧热
Frist, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油滑锅
after heating the wok, add some oil to grease the wok
# 然后将热油倒出加入少许的底油
Pour out the hot oil then add some base oil
# 油温6成热之后加入切好的料头爆香（大蒜，生姜，葱粒）
After reaching ~180°C oil temperature, add the chopped garlic, ginger and spring onion and let the aroma release.```
# 料头爆香之后加入切好的肚条转中火爆炒1分钟
then add the prepared pork tripe strips in, turn the heat to medium and stir-fry for 1 minute
# 爆炒1分钟之后加入1碗煮猪肚的原汤
then add a bowl of pork tripe stock
# 然后转中小火烧3分钟
then turn to medium-low heat and cook for 3 minutes
# 3分钟之后加入切好的笋条和大红椒
after that, add the celtuse and the red pepper
# 下一步开始调味
Next step is seasoning
# 锅中加入食用盐1勺（约2克）
add one teaspoon salt (about 2 grams)
# 加入少许白糖提鲜
add some sugar for umani taste
# 加入少许胡椒粉
add some white pepper powder
# 调好味之后将辅料烧至断生即可
after seasoning, stir fry the minor ingredients until they are just cooked
# 辅料断生之后再加入适量的水淀粉把汤汁勾浓
then add some starch slurry to thicken the sauce
# 最后加入适量的明油翻炒均匀即可出锅装盘
Finally, add some scallion-ginger oil and mix well
# 一道非常美味营养的大蒜烧肚条就制作完成
That is how to cook a delicious and nutritious dish- garlic and tripe strips stir-fry.
# 下面开始技术总结
Here are some key points for cooking
# 第一，猪肚必须加盐，白酒，淀粉抓洗，对酒精过敏的同学可以用白醋代替
1. Must add slat, Baijiu and starch to clean the tripe, if you’re allergic to alcohol, replace Baijiu with rice vinegar.
# 第二，猪肚用高压锅更加节省时间，也可以直接煮40分钟
2. It is more time-saving to use a pressure cooker to cook the pork tripe, if you don't use pressure cooker, you could just boil the pork tripe in a regular pot for 40 minutes.
# 第三，此菜咸鲜微辣特别适合老人孩子食用
3. This dish is not too spicy and has salty-umami style flavor, so it is suitable for elderly and children.
# 大蒜烧肚条的技术总结完毕